eir.ie 2017-12-14

# eir Privacy Statement

We have developed this privacy statement because we want you to feel confident about the privacy and security of your personal details when you visit or use the eir.ie website. We operate a strict opt-in policy for residential customers. We will not send you any information unless you have requested it, or unless someone, who we will identify, has requested that we pass that information on to you. We will not pass on your details to any third party for email or marketing purposes.

eircom Limited is registered with the Data Protection Commissioner as a Data Controller and all handling and processing of your personal data is strictly in accordance with the data protection principles contained in the Data Protection Acts, 1988-2003.

The eir.ie servers are located in a secure facility and any access to your personal data is strictly controlled and limited only to persons who are authorised and have appropriate security clearance to access the servers.

Credit card details are transmitted by eir in an encrypted form to provide extra security for your online transactions.

### Credit Insights:

If you are a new Customer on or after 30th of November 2016 or if you are an existing Customer who enters into a new contract with eir on or after 30th of November 2016 please note if you allow your account to fall into arrears by not paying your bills in full and on time, information on your payment performance may be shared with other service providers of landline, broadband and mobile services through the provision of the information to a database operated by the service providers called Credit Insights.

Other providers of services who also supply information on payment performance of their customers to the Credit Insights database may check this information when you apply for their services in the future to help them assess your credit worthiness. The information shared with Credit Insights includes name, address, date of birth, account details to include account history and balance owed, and will be held on the database for 6 years from the date of the notification of the arrears.

Where you apply to us for post-pay services, we may make searches about you on the Credit Insights database to help us to decide whether to accept your application.

### How we collect information:

You have the option to register on the eir.ie website where you will need to provide us with some personal details to complete registration such as an email address, password, telephone number and account number. This will allow us to provide you with value add services such as viewing and paying your bill online. You can also provide us with additional information, which will allow us to provide you with a more personalised experience whenever you visit our website.

Customers should note that, while eir makes all commercial efforts to protect our customers’ privacy, customers should be aware that information disclosed while connected to the Internet is transferred to the eir servers over a publicly available telecommunications network. eir cannot be held responsible, and accept no liability, for unauthorised access to the public network beyond its reasonable control and all information provided by customers is done entirely at the customers’ own risk.

### How we use your information:

We use your information provided to offer you a more personalised online experience and to inform you of products and services relevant to your needs. Registration also allows you access to value-add services such as e-billing, fault logging and ordering products in the online store. Your personal information may also be used to verify your identity, to protect against fraud, and to send you relevant updates e.g. notification of your bill. eir does not share your information with any third party.

### Opt-in / Opt-out:

We operate a strict opt-in policy for our residential customers. That means we will not send you any information unless you have requested to receive email updates from us.  For business customers, we operate, in compliance with the relevant legislation, an opt-out policy.

If you (whether a residential or business customer) wish to be removed from our list, at any time, (opt-out) you can do so by clicking on the link at the bottom of each email communication you receive from us.

### Use of cookie technology:

The eir website creates a "cookie" when you first register online. A cookie is a piece of information, like a tag, which some websites create against your profile. Our cookie will store some basic information, which helps us to identify if you have visited the site before. This will allow us provide you with personalised content or present you with product and service information based on your previous behaviour on the site.

### How to disable cookies:

If you do not want a cookie to be created on your PC, web browsers such as Netscape and Internet Explorer provide the option to disable them. Please bear in mind that some personalised services on eir.ie, or from other non-eir websites, may not be available if you choose to disable cookies. You can find out more about cookies on [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### Contact us:

If you have any additional questions about our privacy policy or how we collect and use your personal data, please [Contact Us](https://www.eir.ie/group/contactus/).

### Update information:

If you would like to update your registration profile at any stage you can do so by logging into to the website with your email address and visit the 'My eir settings' area.
